13 meters. You should see it.
Okay, take her up and over the bow rail.
Mir 2, we're going over the bow. Stay with us.
Okay, quiet. We're rolling.
Seeing her coming out of the darkness like a ghost ship...
still gets me every time.
To see the sad ruin of the great ship sitting here...
where she landed at 2:30 in the morning
of April 15, 1912...
after her long fall...
from the world above.
You are so full of shit, boss.
Dive 6. Here we are again on the deck of Titanic.
21/2 miles down. 3,821 meters.
The pressure outside is 31/2 tons per square inch.
These windows are 9 inches thick.
If they go, it's sayonara in two microseconds.
All right, enough of that bullshit.
Just put her down on the roof of the officers' quarters like yesterday.
Mir 2, we're landing right over the Grand Staircase. You guys set to launch?
Yeah, Brock. Launching Dunkin now. Go, Charlie.
- All right, tether out.  - Tether out.
Okay, Brock, we're dropping down along the hull.
Yeah, roger that. Okay, drop down and go into the first class gangway door.
I want you guys working the D deck...
reception area and the dining saloon.
Copy that.
- Tether out. Okay, now left. Left, left.  - Okay, coming left.
Snoop Dog is on the move. We're headed down the stairwell.
Okay Lewis, drop down to B deck.
- Okay, A deck.  - Give me some rope, Captain.
B deck. Get in there. Get in there.
Watch the door frame.
- Watch it, watch it.  - I see it. I got it.
- We good? Bring her down.  - We're good. Just chill, boss.
Okay, make your turn.
- Cable out, Captain.  - Make your turn. Watch the wall.
Yeah Brock, we're at the piano. You copy?
Okay, copy that.
Okay, right there. Right there.
Okay, that's it, that's it. That's the bedroom door.
I see it. I see it.
We're in!
We're in, baby. We're there.
That's Hockley's bed.
That's where the son of a bitch slept.
Oops. Somebody left the water running.
Hold it. Hold it just a second. Go back to the right.
That wardrobe door. Get closer.
You smelling something, boss?
- I want to see what's under it.  - Give me my hands, man.
All right.
- Take it easy. It might come apart.  - Okay.
Go, go, go. Flip it over. Flip it over. Go.
Turn her over. Keep going.
Go, go, go.
Okay, drop it.
Oh, baby, baby. Are you seeing this, boss?
It's payday, boys.
Cha-ching!
- We did it, Bobby.  - We brought it back, Baby.
Oh, yeah! Who's the best? Who's the best, baby?
Say it. Say it. Say it.
You are, Lewis.
- Bobby, my cigar.  - Right here.
Okay, crack her open.
Shit.
No diamond.
You know boss, this same thing happened to Geraldo and his career never recovered.
Turn the camera off.
Brock, the partners would like to know how it's going.
Hey, Dave, Barry, hi. Look, I it wasn't in the safe. But hey, hey...
Don't worry about it. There's still plenty of places it could be. Hell, yes.
The floor debris in the suite, the mother's room...
the purser's safe on C deck.
Jimmy Hoffa's briefcase.
A dozen other places. Guys, look, you're just going to have to trust my instincts. I know we're close.
We've just got to go through a little process of elimination.
Hang on a second.
- Let me see that.  - Ah, we may have something here, guys.
Where's the photograph of the necklace?
We'll call you right back.
I'll be goddamned.
Treasure hunter Brock Lovett is best known for finding Spanish gold...
It's okay. I'll feed you in a minute.
Now he has chartered Russian subs to reach the most famous shipwreck of all, the Titanic.
He is with us live via satellite from the research ship Keldysh...
in the North Atlantic. Hello. Brock.
Hello, Tracy. Of course, everyone knows the familiar stories of Titanic.
You know, the nobility of the band playing to the very end and all that.
But what I'm interested in are the untold stories. The secrets locked deep inside the hull of Titanic.
And we're out here using robot technology to go further into the wreck...
than anybody has ever done before.
Your expedition is at the center of a storm of controversy...
over salvage rights and even ethics. Many are calling you a graverobber.
Well, nobody ever called the recovery of the artifacts...
What is it?
Turn that up, dear.
I have museum-trained experts sent out here making sure...
that these relics are preserved and catalogued properly.
Take a look at this drawing that we found just today.
A piece of paper that's been underwater for 84 years.
And my team are able to preserve it intact.
Should this have remained unseen at the bottom of the ocean for eternity...
- when we can see and enjoy it now?  - I'll be goddamned.
Brock!
There's a satellite call for you.
Bobby, we're launching. You see these submersibles going in the water?
Trust me, buddy. You want to take this call.
This better be good.
Now, you gotta speak up. She's kind of old.
Great.
This is Brock Lovett. How can I help you, Mrs...?
Calvert. Rose Calvert.
Mrs. Calvert.
I was just wondering if you had found...
the "Heart of the Ocean" yet, Mr. Lovett.
Told you you wanted to take the call.
All right, you have my attention, Rose.
Can you tell us who the woman in the picture is?
Oh, yes. The woman in the picture is me.
She's a goddamn liar! Some nutcase seeking money or publicity.
God only knows why. Like that Russian babe, Anesthesia.
They're inbound!
Rose DeWitt Bukater died on the Titanic when she was 17, right?
- That's right.  - If she had lived, she'd be over 100 by now.
101 next month.
Okay, so she's a very old goddamn liar.
Look, I've already done the background on this woman...
all the way back to the 20s, when she was working as an actress.
An actress. There's your first clue, Sherlock.
Her name was Rose Dawson back then. Then she marries this guy named Calvert.
They move to Cedar Rapids and she punches out a couple of kids.
Now Calvert's dead and, from what I hear, Cedar Rapids is dead.
And everybody who knows about the diamond is supposed to be dead...
or on this boat, but she knows.
Doesn't exactly travel light, does she?
Hurry up, give him a hand.
Mrs. Calvert, I'm Brock Lovett. Welcome to the Keldysh.
Okay, let's get her inside there.
Hi, Miss Calvert.
- Hi.  - Welcome to the Keldysh.
Thanks.
Hey!
Are your staterooms all right?
Oh, yes.
Very nice.
Have you met my granddaughter, Lizzy?
She takes care of me.
We met just a few minutes ago.
Remember, Nana? Up on deck?
Oh, yes.
There. That's nice.
Have to have my pictures when I travel.
Can I get you anything?
Is there anything you'd like?
Yes.
I would like to see my drawing.
Louis XVI wore a fabulous stone that was...
called the Blue Diamond of the Crown...
which disappeared in 1792...
about the same time old Louis lost everything from the neck up.
The theory goes that the crown diamond was chopped, too.
Recut into a heart-like shape that became known as...
the Heart of the Ocean.
Today it would be worth more than the Hope diamond.
It was a dreadful, heavy thing.
I only wore it this once.
You actually think this is you, Nana?
It is me, dear.
Wasn't I a dish?
I tracked it down through insurance records.
An old claim that was settled under terms of absolute secrecy.
Can you tell me who the claimant was, Rose?
I should imagine someone named Hockley.
Nathan Hockley, that's right.
Pittsburgh steel tycoon.
The claim was for a diamond necklace his son...
Caledon, bought his fiancee.
You.
A week before he sailed on Titanic.
And it was filed right after the sinking.
So the diamond had to have gone down with the ship.
You see the date?
April 14, 1912.
Which means if your grandmother is who she says she is...
she was wearing the diamond the day the Titanic sank.
And that makes you my new best friend.
These are some of the things we recovered from your stateroom.
This was mine.
How extraordinary.
And it looks the same as it did the last time I saw it.
The reflection has changed a bit.
Are you ready to go back to Titanic?
Okay, here we go.
She hits the berg on the starboard side, right?
She kind of bumps along...
punching holes like morse code...
dit-dit-dit... along the side...
below the water line.
Then the forward compartments start to flood.
Now, as the water level rises...
it spills over the watertight bulkheads...
which, unfortunately, don't go any higher than E deck.
So now as the bow goes down...
the stern rises up, slow at first...
then faster and faster...
until finally, she's got her whole ass sticking up in the air.
And that's a big ass.
We're talking 20, 30,000 tons. Okay?
And the hull's not designed to deal with that pressure.
So, what happens?
She splits, right down to the keel.
And the stern...
falls back level.
Then...
as the bow sinks...
it pulls the stern vertical...
and then finally detaches.
Now the stern section just kind of bobs there like a cork for a couple of minutes...
floods, and finally goes under about 2:20 AM...
2 hours and 40 minutes after the collision.
The bow section planes away...
landing about a half a mile away...
going 20, 30 knots when it hits the ocean floor.
Pretty cool, huh?
Thank you for that fine forensic analysis, Mr. Bodine.
Of course, the experience of it was...
somewhat different.
Will you share it with us?
I'm taking her to rest.
No.
Come on, Nana.
No!
Give me the tape recorder.
Tell us, Rose.
It's been 84 years...
It's okay. Just try to remember anything...
anything at all.
Do you want to hear this or not, Mr. Lovett?
It's been 84 years...
and I can still smell the fresh paint.
The china had never been used.
The sheets had never been slept in.
Titanic was called the ship of dreams.
And it was.
It really was.
All third-class passengers...
with a forward berth...
this way please! This queue!
It's a big boat, huh?
Daddy, it's a ship.
You're right.
I don't see what all the fuss is about.
It doesn't look any bigger than the Mauretania.
You can be blase about some things, Rose...
but not about Titanic.
It's over 100 feet longer than Mauretania...
and far more luxurious.
Your daughter is far too difficult to impress, Ruth.
So this is the ship they say is unsinkable.
It is unsinkable.
God Himself could not sink this ship...
What?!
You have to check your baggage through the main terminal.
It's round that way, sir.
I put my faith in you good sir.
Now kindly see my man.
Yes sir. It's my pleasure, sir.
If I can do anything at all...
Yes, right.
All the trunks from that car there.
12 from here.
And the safe, to the parlor suite...
rooms B52, 54, 56.
Ladies...
we better hurry.
Come along.
- My coat?  - I have it, miss.
All third-class passengers queue here for health inspection.
- Welcome aboard, ma'am.  - Welcome to Titanic.
It was the ship of dreams...
to everyone else.
To me. It was a slave ship...
taking me back to America in chains.
Outwardly, I was everything a well brought up girl should be.
Inside, I was screaming.
Jack, you are pazzo.
You bet everything we have.
When you got nothing, you got nothing to lose.
You moron. I can't believe you bet our tickets.
Sven?
All right, moment of truth.
Someone's life is about to change.
Fabrizio?
Niente.
Olaf?
Nothing.
Sven?
Uh-oh. 2 pair.
I'm sorry, Fabrizio.
I'm sorry...
you're not gonna see your mom again for a long time.
'cause we're going to America.
Full house, boys!
Come on.
I'm going home!
I'm going home.
I go to America!
No, mate.
Titanic go to America,
in 5 minutes.
Shit. Fabri. Come on.
Come on, here. Here.
We're riding in high style now!
We're a couple of regular swells.
We're practically goddamn royalty...
ragazzo mio.
You see? Is my destino.
Like I told you...
I go to America to be millionaire.
You are pazzo.
Maybe, but I've got the tickets.
Come on, I thought you were fast.
Aspetta!
Whoa. Wait! Wait!
Hey, wait!
We're passengers!
Have you been through the inspection queue?
Of course.
Anyway, we don't have any lice.
We're Americans. Both of us.
Right.
Come aboard.
We're the luckiest sons of bitches in the world.
You know that?
Good-bye!
You know somebody?
Of course not. That's not the point.
Good-bye! I'll miss you!
Good-bye!
I will never forget you!
Come with me, darling. Let's go.
G60.
G60. G60.
Excuse me, ma'am.
G60.
Oh, right here.
Hey, how you doing?
Jack. Nice to meet you.
Jack Dawson. Nice to meet you.
How you doing?
Who says you get top bunk, huh?
This is your private promenade deck, sir.
Will you be requiring anything?
Excuse me.
- This one?  - No.
It had a lot of faces on it.
This is the one.
Would you like all of them out, miss?
Yes. We need a little color in this room.
Put in there. In the wardrobe.
God, not those finger paintings again.
They certainly were a waste of money.
The difference between Cal's taste in art...
and mine is that I have some.
They're fascinating.
Like being inside a dream or something.
There's truth but no logic.
- What's the artist's name?  - Something Picasso.
Something Picasso.
He won't amount to a thing.
He won't, trust me.
- Let's put the Degas in the bedroom.  - At least they were cheap.
Put it in the wardrobe.
At Cherbourg, a woman came aboard named Margaret Brown.
We all called her Molly.
History would call her the Unsinkable Molly Brown.
Well, I wasn't about to wait all day for you, sonny.
Here, if you think you can manage.
Her husband had struck gold someplace out west.
And she was what Mother called "new money."
By the next afternoon...
we were steaming west from the coast of Ireland...
with nothing out ahead of us but ocean.
Take her to sea, Mr. Murdoch.
Let's stretch her legs.
Yes sir.
All ahead full, Mr. Moody.
Very good, sir.
All ahead full.
All ahead full!
Come on lads, step lively!
All right! Let's stoke her right up!
We go full ahead!
Come on, put your backs into it!
21 knots, sir.
Hey, look, look, look!
See it?
There's another one! See him?
Look at that one! Look at him jump!
I can see the Statue of Liberty already.
Very small, of course.
I'm the king of the world!
She is the largest moving object ever made by the hand of man...
in all history.
And our master shipbuilder, Mr. Andrews here...
designed her from the keel plates up.
I may have knocked her together, but...
the idea was Mr. Ismay's.
He envisioned a steamer so grand in scale...
and so luxurious in...
its appointments...
that its supremacy would never be challenged.
And here she is.
- Willed into solid reality.  - Hear, hear.
I'll have the salmon.
You know I don't like that, Rose.
She knows.
We'll both have the lamb.
Rare, with very little mint sauce.
You like lamb, right sweet pea?
You gonna cut her meat for her too there, Cal?
Hey, who thought of the name Titanic?
Was it you, Bruce?
Yes, actually.
I wanted to convey sheer size. And size means stability...
luxury, and above all, strength.
Do you know of Dr. Freud, Mr. Ismay?
His ideas about the male preoccupation with size might be of particular interest to you.
What's gotten into you?
Excuse me.
I do apologize.
She's a pistol, Cal. Hope you can handle her.
Well, I may have to start minding what she reads from now on, won't I, Mrs. Brown?
Freud? Who is he? Is he a passenger?
The ship is nice, huh?
Yeah. It's an Irish ship.
Is English, no?
No, it was built in Ireland.
15,000 Irishmen built this ship.
Solid as a rock. Big Irish hands.
That's typical.
First-class dogs come down here to take a shite.
Lets us know where we rank in the scheme of things.
Like we could forget?
I'm Tommy Ryan.
- Jack Dawson.  - Fabrizio.
Do you make any money with your drawings?
Ah, forget it, boyo.
You'd as like have angels fly out of your arse as get next to...
the likes of her.
I saw my whole life as if I'd already lived it.
An endless parade of parties and cotillions...
yachts and polo matches.
Always the same narrow people, the same mindless chatter.
I felt like I was standing at a great precipice...
with no one to pull me back. No one who cared...
or even noticed.
Don't do it.
Stay back.
Don't come any closer.
Come on.
Just give me your hand. I'll pull you back over.
No! Stay where you are.
I mean it.
I'll let go.
No, you won't.
What do you mean, no I won't?
Don't presume to tell me what I will and will not do.
You don't know me.
Well, you would have done it already.
You're distracting me. Go away.
I can't.
I'm involved now.
You let go, and I'm going to have to jump in there after you.
Don't be absurd.
- You'll be killed.  - I'm a good swimmer.
The fall alone will kill you.
It would hurt. I'm not saying it wouldn't.
Tell you the truth...
I'm a lot more concerned about that water being so cold.
How cold?
Freezing. Maybe a couple degrees over.
You ever, uh...
ever been to Wisconsin?
What?
Well, they have some of the coldest winters around.
I grew up there, near Chippewa Falls.
I remember when I was a kid, me and my father, we went ice fishing...
out on Lake Wissota.
Ice fishing is, you know, where you...
I know what ice fishing is!
Sorry.
You just seem like, you know, kind of an indoor girl.
Anyway, I...
fell through some thin ice.
And I'm telling you...
water that cold,
like right down there...
it hits you like 1000 knives stabbing you all over your body.
You can't breathe.
You can't think. Least not about anything but the pain.
Which is why I'm not looking forward to jumping in there after you.
Like I said...
I don't have a choice.
I guess I'm kind of hoping you'll come back over the rail and...
and get me off the hook here.
You're crazy.
That's what everybody says but...
with all due respect, miss...
I'm not the one hanging off the back of a ship here.
Come on.
Come on, give me your hand.
You don't want to do this.
I'm Jack Dawson.
Rose Dewitt Bukater.
I'll have to get you to write that one down.
Come on.
I got you.
Help, please!
Help!
- Please, help me!  - Listen. Listen to me.
Listen. Listen to me.
I've got you. I won't let go.
Now pull yourself up. Come on!
Come on.
That's right.
You can do it.
I got you.
What's all this?
You stand back and...
don't move an inch!
Fetch the Master at Arms.
This is completely unacceptable!
What made you think that you could put your hands on my fiancee?!
Look at me, you filth!
Cal.
What do you think you were doing?
Cal, stop. It was an accident.
An accident?
It was.
Stupid, really.
I was leaning over and I slipped.
I was leaning far over to see the, uh...
uh, uh, the uh...
- Propellers?  - Propellers, and I slipped.
And I would have gone overboard but Mr. Dawson here...
saved me. And almost went over himself.
You wanted to see the... She wanted to see the propellers.
Like I said, women and machinery do not mix.
Was that the way of it?
Yeah. Yeah, that was pretty much it.
Well, the boy's a hero then.
Good for you, son. Well done.
So, it's all's well and back to our brandy, eh?
Look at you. You must be freezing. Let's get you inside.
Perhaps a little something for the boy?
Of course.
Mr. Lovejoy, I think a 20 should do it.
Is that the going rate for saving the woman you love?
Rose is displeased.
What to do?
I know.
Perhaps you could join us for dinner tomorrow evening...
to regale our group...
with your heroic tale.
Sure. Count me in.
Good. It's settled then.
This should be interesting.
Can I bum a smoke?
You'll want to tie those.
It's interesting...
the young lady slipped so suddenly...
and you still had time to remove your jacket and your shoes.
I know you've been melancholy.
I don't pretend to know why.
I intended to save this...
until the engagement gala next week...
but, I thought...
tonight.
Good gracious.
Perhaps as a reminder of my feelings for you.
- Is it a...  - Diamond. Yes.
56 carats to be exact.
It was worn by Louis XVI.
And they called it Le Coeur de la Mer.
- The Heart of the Ocean.  - The Heart of the Ocean. Yes.
It's overwhelming.
Well, it's for royalty.
We are royalty, Rose.
You know, there's nothing I couldn't give you.
There's nothing I'd deny you...
if you would not deny me.
Open your heart to me, Rose.
Well, I've been on my own since I was 15, since my folks died.
And I had no brothers or sisters or close kin in that part of the country...
so I lit on out of there and I haven't been back since.
You could just call me a tumbleweed blowing in the wind.
Well, Rose, we've walked about a mile around this boat deck and...
chewed over how great the weather's been and how I grew up...
but I reckon that's not why you came to talk to me, is it?
- Mr. Dawson, I...  - Jack.
Jack.
I want to thank you for what you did.
Not just for pulling me back, but for your discretion.
You're welcome.
Look.
I know what you must be thinking.
Poor little rich girl.
What does she know about misery?
No.
No, that's not what I was thinking.
What I was thinking was...
what could have happened to this girl to make her think she had no way out?
Well I...
It was everything. It was my whole world and...
all the people in it.
And the inertia of my life, plunging ahead and me...
powerless to stop it.
God, look at that thing.
You would have gone straight to the bottom.
500 invitations have gone out.
All of Philadelphia society will be there.
And all the while I feel I'm...
standing in the middle of a crowded room...
screaming at the top of my lungs...
and no one even looks up.
Do you love him?
Pardon me?
You're being very rude. You shouldn't be asking me this.
Well, it's a simple question. Do you love the guy or not?
This is not a suitable conversation.
Why can't you just answer the question?
This is absurd.
You don't know me and I don't know you...
and we are not having this conversation at all. You are rude...
and uncouth and presumptuous and I am leaving now...
Jack. Mr.Dawson. It's been a pleasure.
I sought you out to thank you and now I have thanked you.
And you've insulted me.
Well, you deserved it.
- Right.  - Right.
I thought you were leaving.
I am.
You are so annoying.
Wait.
I don't have to leave. This is my part of the ship. You leave.
Well, well, well. Now who's being rude?
What is this stupid thing you're carrying around?
So, what are you, an artist or something?
These are rather good.
They're very good, actually.
Jack, this is exquisite work.
Ah, they didn't think too much of them in old Paree.
Paris?
You do get around for a P...
Well, a... a person of limited means.
Go on. A poor guy. You can say it.
Well, well, well.
And these were drawn from life?
Well, that's one of the good things about Paris.
Lots of girls are willing to take their clothes off.
You liked this woman.
You used her several times.
Well.
She had beautiful hands, you see?
I think you must have had a love affair with her.
No, no, no. Just with her hands.
She was a one-legged prostitute.
See?
She had a good sense of humor though.
Oh, and this lady...
She used to sit at this bar every night...
wearing every piece of jewelry she owned...
just waiting for her long, lost love.
We called her Madame Bijoux.
See, her clothes are all moth-eaten.
Well, you have a gift, Jack.
You do.
You see people.
I see you.
And?
You wouldn't have jumped.
But the purpose of university is to find a suitable husband.
Rose has already done that.
Look, here comes that vulgar Brown woman.
Quickly, get up before she sits with us.
Hello, girls. I was hoping I'd catch you at tea.
We're awfully sorry, you missed it.
The Countess and I were just off to take the air on the boat deck.
What a lovely idea. I need to catch up on my gossip.
Countess.
So, you've not yet lit the last four boilers?
No, I don't see the need.
We are making excellent time.
The press knows the size of Titanic. Now, I want them to marvel at her speed.
We must give them something new to print.
This maiden voyage of Titanic must...
make headlines.
Mr.Ismay, I would prefer not to push the engines...
until they've been properly run in.
Of course I'm just a passenger.
I leave it to your good offices to decide what's best.
But what a glorious end to your final crossing...
if we were to get into New York on Tuesday night...
and surprise them all. Make the morning papers.
Retire with a bang, eh, E.J?
Good man.
After that, I worked on a squid boat in Monterey...
then I went to Los Angeles to the...
Santa Monica pier and did portraits for 10 cents each.
Why can't I be like you?
Just head out for the horizon whenever I feel like it.
Say we'll go there sometime, to that pier...
only if we just talk about it.
No, we'll do it. We'll drink cheap beer.
Ride on the roller coaster till we throw up.
We'll ride horses on the beach, in the surf.
But you have to do it like a real cowboy. No sidesaddle stuff.
You mean with one leg on each side?
Can you show me?
Sure, if you like.
Teach me to ride like a man.
Chew tobacco like a man.
And spit like a man.
You didn't learn in finishing school?
No.
Come on, I'll show you.
I'll show you how.
Jack! No, Jack, no. Wait.
I couldn't possibly, Jack.
Watch closely.
That's disgusting.
Your turn.
That was pitiful. You really have to hawk it back.
Get some leverage. Use your arms. Arc your neck.
You see the range on that thing?
Okay, go.
That was better. You have to work on it. Really try to hawk it up.
Mother.
May I introduce Jack Dawson?
Charmed, I'm sure.
The others were gracious and curious about the man who'd saved my life.
But my mother looked at him like an insect.
A dangerous insect which must be squashed quickly.
Sounds like you're a good man to have around in a sticky spot.
Why do they always insist on announcing dinner like a damn cavalry charge?
Shall we go dress, Mother?
See you at dinner, Jack.
Uh, son?
Son!
Do you have any idea what you're doing?
Not really.
You're about to go into the snake pit.
What are you going to wear?
I figured. Come on.
I was right. You and my son are just about the same size.
Pretty close.
You shine up like a new penny.
Good evening, sir.
Thousands of tons of Hockley steel are in this ship.
- Which part?  - All the right ones.
Then you're accountable if there's a problem. Where's Rose?
She'll be along.
There is the Countess.
I saw that in a nickelodeon and always wanted to do it.
Darling...
surely you remember Mr.Dawson.
It's amazing. You could almost pass for a gentleman.
Almost.
This is extraordinary.
This is a remarkable voyage.
- Mad.  - Completely lunatic.
There's the Countess of Rothes.
That's John Jacob Astor...
the richest man on board.
His little wifey, Madeleine, is my age and in a delicate condition.
See how she tries to hide it.
Quite the scandal.
Benjamin Guggenheim and his mistress, Madame Aubert. Mrs.Guggenheim...
is at home with the children, of course. And over here...
Sir Cosmo and Lucile, Lady Duff-Gordon.
She designs naughty lingerie, among her many talents.
Very popular with the royals.
Congratulations. She's splendid.
Why, thank you.
Escort a lady to dinner?
Certainly.
Sweet pea, sweet pea.
Ain't nothing to it.
They love money. Pretend like you own a gold mine and you're in the club.
Hey, Astor.
Hello, Molly. Nice to see you.
J.J., Madeleine, I'd like you to meet Jack Dawson.
Well, Jack...
are you of the Boston Dawsons?
No, the Chippewa Falls Dawsons, actually.
Oh, yes.
He must have been nervous. But he never faltered.
They assumed he was one of them.
Heir to a railroad fortune, perhaps.
New money, obviously, but still a member of the club.
Mother. Of course. Could always be counted upon.
Tell us of the accommodations in steerage, Mr.Dawson. I hear they're quite good.
The best I've seen, ma'am. Hardly any rats.
Mr.Dawson is joining us from third class.
He was of help to my fiancee last night.
It happens Mr.Dawson is quite a fine artist.
He showed me some of his work today.
Rose and I differ in our definition of fine art. Not to impugn your work, sir.
Are all these mine?
Start from the outside and work in.
He knows every rivet in her.
Your ship is a wonder, Mr.Andrews.
Thank you, Rose.
How do you take your caviar, sir?
No caviar for me, thanks. Never did like it much.
Where exactly do you live, Mr.Dawson?
Right now, my address is the RMS Titanic.
After that, I'm on God's good humor.
How do you have means to travel?
I work my way from place to place. Tramp steamers and such.
I won my ticket on Titanic at a lucky hand at poker.
A very lucky hand.
All life is a game of luck.
A real man makes his own luck. Right, Dawson?
And you find that sort of rootless existence appealing?
Yes, ma'am, I do.
I've got everything I need right here with me.
I have air in my lungs and blank sheets of paper.
I love waking up, not knowing what will happen or who I'll meet.
Where I'll wind up.
One night I'm sleeping under a bridge...
now I'm on the grandest ship in the world having champagne with you fine people.
I'll take more of that.
Life's a gift. I don't intend on wasting it.
You never know what hand you'll get dealt.
You take life as it comes at you. Here, Cal.
Make each day count.
Well said, Jack.
Hear, hear.
To making it count.
Bravo.
But Mr.Brown didn't know I'd hidden the money in the stove.
He comes home drunk as a pig celebrating and lights a fire.
Next is brandy in the smoking room.
Join me in a brandy, gentlemen?
Now they retreat to congratulate each other on being masters of the universe.
Ladies, thank you for your company.
May I escort you to the cabin?
No, I'll stay here.
Here, Molly.
Joining us, Dawson?
You don't want to stay with the women.
No, thanks. I have to head back.
That's best. It'll be all business and politics. Wouldn't interest you.
But Dawson, good of you to come.
Must you go?
Time for me to row with the other slaves.
Good night, Rose.
Want to go to a real party?
Is okay I put my hand here?
I can't understand you.
I'm going to dance with her now.
Come on.
Come on. Come with me.
Jack. Jack, wait.
I can't do this.
We'll have to get a bit closer.
Like this.
You're still my best girl, Cora.
- I don't know the steps.  - Me, either. Just go with it.
Don't think.
Wait! Jack! Wait! Stop, Jack!
What? Wait!
Jack, no.
Beyond the jurisdiction of the Sherman Act.
That's what Rockefeller said... Supreme Court didn't swallow it.
What? You think a first-class girl can't drink?
Get out of here.
Are you all right?
I'm fine.
Two out of three.
So...
you think you're tough?
Let's see you do this.
Hold this for me, Jack. Hold it up.
Jesus!
You okay?
I haven't done that in years.
Come on, lads. Give it all you got. Let's go.
Coffee, sir?
You didn't come to me last night.
I was tired.
Your exertions below deck were no doubt exhausting.
I see you had that undertaker of a manservant follow me.
You will never behave like that again.
I'm not one of your mill foremen who you can command.
I'm your fiancee.
My fiancee. My fiancee!
Yes, you are! And my wife!
My wife in practice, if not yet by law, so you will honor me!
You will honor me the way a wife honors her husband.
Because I will not be made a fool of.
Is this in any way unclear?
No.
Good. Excuse me.
Oh, Miss Rose.
We had a little accident.
- That's all right.  - I'm sorry.
Let me help you.
It's all right, miss.
- Tea, Trudy.  - Yes, Ma'am.
You're not to see that boy again. You understand?
Rose, I forbid it.
Stop it, Mother. You'll give yourself a nosebleed.
This is not a game.
Our situation is precarious. You know the money's gone.
Of course I know. You remind me every day.
Your father left us nothing but a legacy of bad debts hidden by a good name.
That name is the only card we have to play.
I don't understand you.
It is a fine match with Hockley. It will ensure our survival.
How can you put this on me?
Why are you being so selfish?
I'm being selfish?
Do you want to see me working as a seamstress?
Is that what you want?
To see our fine things sold at auction?
Our memories scattered?
It's so unfair.
Of course it's unfair.
We're women.
Our choices are never easy.
Protect them by Thy guiding hand
From every peril on the land
O, spirit whom the Father sent
To spread abroad the firmament
O, wind of heaven, by Thy might
Save all who dare the eagle's flight
And keep them by Thy watchful care...
- Hello, Mr. Andrews.  - Hello, Jack.
I need to talk to someone.
You're not supposed to be in here.
I was here last night, remember?
No. Now please turn around.
He'll tell you. I just need to talk...
Mr. Hockley and Mrs. DeWitt Bukater...
are still appreciative of your assistance.
They asked me to give you this in gratitude...
I don't want your money.
And remind you you are in third class and your presence here...
is no longer appropriate.
Let me speak to Rose.
Gentlemen, please see Mr. Dawson returns to where he belongs...
and that he stays there?
Yes, sir.
Come along, you.
Hear us when we cry to Thee
For those in peril on the sea
Why are there two steering wheels?
We use this one near shore.
Excuse me, sir. Another ice warning, from the Noordam.
Thank you, Sparks.
Not to worry. Quite normal for this time of year.
In fact, we're speeding up. I've ordered the last boilers lit.
Okay, son, wind it up tight like I showed you. That's right.
Okay, now let it go.
- It was good, wasn't it?  - Quite nice. That's excellent.
Mr. Andrews... Forgive me.
I did the sum in my head...
and with the number of lifeboats times the capacity you mentioned...
Forgive me, but it seems that there are not enough for everyone aboard.
About half, actually.
Rose, you miss nothing, do you?
In fact, I put in these new type davits...
which can take an extra row of boats inside this one.
But it was thought, by some...
the deck would look too cluttered.
So, I was overruled.
It's a waste of deck space as it is on an unsinkable ship.
Sleep soundly, young Rose.
I have built you a good ship, strong and true.
She's all the lifeboat you need.
Just keep heading aft. The next stop will be the engine room.
Jack, this is impossible. I can't see you.
- I need to talk to you.  - No, Jack. No.
Jack. I'm engaged.
I'm marrying Cal.
I love Cal.
Rose...
you're no picnic. All right? You're a spoiled little brat even.
But under that, you're the most amazingly, astounding...
wonderful girl...
woman, that I've ever known.
Jack, I...
No, let me try and get this out. You're ama...
I'm not an idiot. I know how the world works.
I've got ten bucks in my pocket.
I have nothing to offer you and I know that.
I understand.
But I'm too involved now.
You jump, I jump. Remember?
I can't turn away without knowing you'll be all right.
That's all that I want.
Well, I'm fine.
I'll be fine. Really.
Really?
I don't think so.
They've got you trapped, Rose.
And you're gonna die if you don't break free.
Maybe not right away...
because you're strong...
but sooner or later that fire that I love about you, Rose...
that fire is gonna burn out.
It's not up to you to save me, Jack.
You're right.
Only you can do that.
I'm going back.
Leave me alone.
Tell Lucile about the disaster you had with the stationers.
Well, of course the invitations had to be sent back, twice.
Oh, my dear.
And the dreadful bridesmaids' gowns.
Let me tell you what an odyssey that has been.
Rose decided she wanted lavender.
She knows I detest the color.
So, she did it only to spite me.
If only you'd come to me sooner.
Ruth saw some of my designs in La Mode Illustree.
They were for the trousseau of the Duchess of Marlborough's youngest daughter.
They were quite charming.
But, I think you'll agree, my dear, that together...
we've created something of a phoenix from the ashes.
Hello, Jack.
I changed my mind.
They said you might be up here.
Give me your hand.
Now close your eyes.
Go on.
Now, step up.
Now, hold onto the railing.
Keep your eyes closed. Don't peek.
I'm not.
Now, step up onto the rail.
Hold on. Hold on.
Keep your eyes closed.
Do you trust me?
I trust you.
All right...
open your eyes.
I'm flying.
Jack.
Come, Josephine, in my flying machine. Going up...
she goes. Up she goes.
That was the last time Titanic ever saw daylight.
We're up to dusk the night of the sinking.
6 hours to go.
Incredible. There's Smith and he's standing there and...
he's got the iceberg warning in his fucking hand...
excuse me... his hand, and he's ordering more speed.
26 years of experience working against him.
He figures anything big enough to sink, the ship...
they're gonna see in time to turn.
But the ship's too big with too small a rudder.
Doesn't corner worth a damn.
Everything he knows is wrong.
It's quite proper, I assure you. This is the sitting room.
- Will this light do?  - What?
Don't artists need good light?
That is true, but I'm not used to working in...
such horrible conditions.
Monet!
- Do you know his work?  - Of course.
Look at his use of color here. Isn't he great?
I know. It's extraordinary.
Cal insists on carting this hideous thing everywhere.
Should we be expecting him any time soon?
Not as long as the cigars and brandy hold out.
That's nice.
What is it, a sapphire?
A diamond.
A very rare diamond.
Jack, I want you to draw me like one of your French girls.
Wearing this.
All right.
Wearing only this.
The last thing I need is another picture of me looking like a porcelain doll.
As a paying customer...
I expect to get what I want.
Over on the bed ... uh, the couch.
Come. Lie down.
- Tell me when it looks right.  - Keep that.
Put your arm back the way it was.
Put that other arm up, that hand right by your face there.
Right.
Now, head down.
Eyes to me. Keep them on me.
And try to stay still.
So serious.
I believe you are blushing, Mr. Big Artiste.
I can't imagine Monsieur Monet blushing.
He does landscapes.
- Just relax your face.  - Sorry.
No laughing.
My heart was pounding the whole time.
It was the most erotic moment of my life...
up until then, at least.
So what happened next?
You mean, did we do it?
Sorry to disappoint you, Mr. Bodine.
Jack was very professional.
Thank you.
What are you doing?
Will you put this back in the safe for me?
Gentlemen, would you excuse me.
None of the stewards have seen her.
This is absurd. It's a ship.
There's only so many places she could be.
Lovejoy, find her.
- Clear.  - Yes.
I don't think I've ever seen such a flat calm.
Like a mill pond.
Not a breath of wind.
It will make the bergs harder to see...
with no breaking water at the base.
Well, I'm off.
Maintain speed and heading, Mr. Lightoller.
Yes, sir.
It's getting cold. You look nice.
Miss Rose?
My drawings!
Come on!
Wait, wait, wait!
- Go. Go. Down, down.  - Take us down, quickly. Quickly!
Bye.
Sorry.
- Keep going.  - Thank you, I've got it.
Pretty tough for a valet, this fella.
Seems more like a cop.
I think he was.
- Oh, shit.  - Go!
No, over here!
Quick!
Now what?
What?
More coal for number one, mate.
Hold up? What are you two doing down here?
You shouldn't be down here.
It could be dangerous!
Carry on!
Don't mind us. You're doing a great job!
Keep up the good work!
Look at what we have here, huh?
Thank you.
Where to, miss?
To the stars.
You nervous?
No.
Put your hands on me, Jack.
It's bloody cold.
You know, I can smell ice, you know. When it's near.
Bollocks!
Well, I can, all right?
Did you ever find those binoculars for the lookouts?
Haven't seen them since Southampton.
Well, I'll be on my rounds.
Cheerio.
You're trembling.
Don't worry.
I'll be all right.
- They ran down there.  - Right.
Anything missing?
I have a better idea.
Got you!
Did you see those guys' faces?
Did you see them?
When the ship docks...
I'm getting off with you.
This is crazy.
I know. It doesn't make any sense.
That's why I trust it.
Here, look at this.
Look at that, would you?
They're warmer than we are.
If that's what it takes for us to get warm, I'd rather not.
Bugger me!
Pick up, you bastards!
Is anyone there?!
What do you see?
Iceberg, right ahead!
Thank you.
Iceberg ahead!
Hard a' starboard!
Turn! Turn! Smartly!
Full astern!
Hard over.
Helm's hard over, sir.
Go, lads, go!
Bring that steam down! Bring it down!
Shut all the dampers! Shut them!
Hold it.
Hold it!
Now! Engage reversing engine!
Why ain't they turning?
Is it hard over?!
It is, sir. Hard over.
Come on, come on, come on. Turn.
Yes.
It's going to hit!
Jesus Christ!
Jesus!
Hard to port!
Get back!
Let's go!
Get in the doors! They're closing the doors! Get out!
Get out the door! Go!
Go! Come on, lads! Go, lads, go!
Go! Go!
Out! Out!
Oh, my God.
That was a close shave.
Smell ice, can you? Bleedin' Christ!
Note the time. Enter it in the log.
What was that, Mr. Murdoch?
An iceberg, sir.
I put her hard to starboard, and the engines full astern, but it was too close.
I tried to port round it, but she hit...
- Close the watertight doors.  - They're closed, sir.
All stop.
Have the carpenter sound the ship.
Come on, let's get the hell out of here!
Why have the engines stopped? I felt a shudder.
Not to worry. We threw a propeller blade.
That's the shudder you felt. Do you need anything?
No, thank you.
There's talk of an iceberg.
I don't see anything. Do you?
If this is where the rats are going, I am, too.
- You there.  - There is no emergency.
- There is. I've been robbed.  - Get the Master at Arms.
Now, you moron!
Did I miss the fun?
- Did you see what happened?  - No. I missed it. Apparently it hit over there.
Boiler room six is flooded eight feet and the mail hold is worse. She's all buckled in in the forward hold.
- Can you shore up?  - Not unless the pumps get ahead.
- Have you seen the mail hold?  - It's already underwater.
This is bad.
We should tell Mother and Cal.
I think they're very good, sir.
Don't touch anything. I want the room photographed.
We've been looking for you, miss.
Here we go.
Something serious has happened.
Yes, it has.
Indeed. Two things dear to me have disappeared.
Now that one is back, I know where to find the other. Search him.
- Take your coat off.  - Now what?
What are you doing? We're in the middle of an emergency.
- Is this it?  - That's it.
This is horseshit!
Don't you believe it.
- He couldn't have.  - Easy enough for a professional.
I was with him the entire time. This is absurd.
Perhaps he did it while you were putting your clothes back on, dear.
Real slick. They put it in my pocket.
- Shut up.  - It isn't even your pocket.
"Property of A.L. Ryerson."
That was reported stolen today.
I just borrowed it.
Oh, we have an honest thief.
You know I didn't do this, Rose.
Don't believe them. You know it.
Let's go, son.
You know I didn't do it!
There's a good lad. Come on.
You know I didn't do it! You know me!
This is most unfortunate, Captain.
Water fourteen feet above the keel in ten minutes...
in the forepeak, all three holds and boiler room six.
That's right.
When can we get underway?
That's five compartments.
She can float with four compartments breached, but not five.
Not five. As she goes down by the head, the water will spill...
over the tops of the bulkheads at E deck, one to the next...
back and back. There's no stopping it.
The pumps. If we opened the doors...
The pumps buy you time, but minutes only.
As of now, no matter what we do...
Titanic will founder.
But this ship can't sink.
She's made of iron. I assure you, she can.
And she will.
It's a mathematical certainty.
How much time?
An hour. Two, at most.
How many aboard, Mr. Murdoch?
Two thousand, two hundred souls, sir.
Well, I believe you may get your headlines, Mr. Ismay.
Oh, it is a little slut, isn't it?
Look at me when I'm talking to you!
- Mr. Hockley?  - Not now. We're busy.
You've been asked to put on lifebelts and go to the boat deck.
I said, not now.
I'm sorry, Mr. Hockley, but it's Captain's orders. Dress warmly.
It's quite cold out.
May I suggest topcoats and hats?
This is ridiculous.
Not to worry, miss. I'm sure it's just a precaution.
Everybody up! Lifebelts on!
What's he on about?
- Put your lifebelts on!  - What is it?
Just put them on.
C.Q. D?
Sir?
That's right, C.Q.D. The distress call. That's our position.
Tell whoever responds we're going down by the head and need immediate assistance.
Blimey.
Keep lowering!
Steady! Make it taut! And winch out!
Uncover this boat! Uncover all the boats aft!
Release those ties!
Roll back that cover! Smartly now!
Where are the passengers?
They went inside. Too cold and noisy for them.
You there! Get down here and help with these lines!
Care for a drink, sir?
Sonny, what's doing? You get us all trussed up and now we're cooling our heels.
Sorry, ma'am. Let me go find out.
Nobody knows what's going on.
Just like the damn English... everything by the book.
No need for language, Mr. Hockley.
Go back and turn on the heaters in our rooms. I want a cup of tea when I return.
Mr. Andrews.
I saw the iceberg. And I see it in your eyes.
Please tell me the truth.
The ship will sink.
You're certain?
In an hour or so, all this will be at the bottom of the Atlantic.
Please, tell only who you must. I don't want to cause a panic.
And get to a boat. Quickly. Don't wait.
You remember what I told you about the boats?
Yes.
I understand.
Over here, son.
Sir, there's a big mob at the Second Class Purser's office.
Go on. I'll watch him.
Aye. Right.
Sir, Carpathia says they're making 17 knots. Full steam for them, sir.
She's the only one responding?
The only one close. They'll be here in four hours.
Four hours?!
Thank you, Bride.
My God.
We are swung out and ready, sir.
Hadn't we better get the women and children into the boats?
Yes.
Women and children first, yes.
Yes, sir.
Ladies and gentlemen, attention, please!
Step this way, please. That's right.
Come towards me. Thank you.
Good.
For the time being, I require only women and children.
Right here.
Like the Captain said, nice and cheery, so there's no panic.
"Wedding Dance."
Lifebelts on. Put your lifebelts on.
Put your lifebelts on. Lifebelt on.
Here, put that lifebelt on. Turn that around.
It isn't time to go to the boats yet!
Please, stay calm.
Make sure you have your lifebelts on.
Let women and children through to the front.
What are we doing, mummy?
Waiting. Once first-class people are in the boats...
they'll start with us and we want to be ready.
Pushing won't get you out any faster.
Go get help.
Lower it away, left and right together! Steady.
Both sides together! Steady!
Steady!
Stop, stop, stop!
Hold the left!
Right side only! Right side only!
Right side!
Hold the left! Right side down! Lower away together!
Steady, lads!
You know, I do believe this ship may sink.
I've been asked to give you this small token of our appreciation.
Compliments of Mr. Caledon Hockley.
Come on, sister, you heard the man. Into the boat.
Any room for a gentleman, gentlemen?
Only women at this time, sir.
Will the lifeboats be seated according to class?
I hope they're not too crowded.
Oh, Mother, shut up!
Don't you understand?
The water is freezing and there aren't enough boats.
Not enough by half.
Half the people on this ship are going to die.
Not the better half.
Come on, Ruth, get in the boat.
First class seats are right up here.
You know, it's a pity I didn't keep that drawing.
It'll be worth a lot more by morning.
You unimaginable bastard.
Come on, Rose darling. There's plenty of room for you.
Come on, Rose.
You're next, darling.
Come into the boat, Rose.
Come.
Rose.
Get into the boat!
Good-bye, Mother.
Where are you going?
To him?!
To be a whore to a gutter rat?
I'd rather be his whore than your wife.
No!
I said, no!
Rose! Please, stop!
And, lower away!
No, Wait!
Lower away!
- Rose!  - Lower together!
Hold the left side!
Help!
Can anybody hear me?!
Hello! Help me!
Help me!
Can you hear me?!
Can anybody hear me?! Somebody help me!
Mr. Andrews?!
Steward, check the starboard corridor.
Madame, please put on a lifebelt. Get to the boat deck immediately.
Lucy, for God's sake put on your lifebelt and set a good example.
Yes sir.
- Anyone in here?  - Mr. Andrews!
Mr. Andrews! Thank God!
Where would the Master at Arms take someone under arrest?
What? You have to get to a boat right away.
No!
I'm doing this with or without your help, sir.
But without will take longer.
Take the elevator to the very bottom. Go to the left...
down the crewmen's passage.
Then go right and left again at the stairs.
You'll come to a long corridor.
This could be bad.
Oh, shit! Oh, shit!
Excuse me. Thank you.
I'm sorry, miss, but the lifts are closed.
I'm through being polite, goddamnit!
Now take me down!
E deck.
Come on.
Come on, come on.
I'm going back up.
No! No! No!
Come back! I'm going back up!
I'm going back up!
Crew passage.
Jack!
Rose!
Rose, I'm in here!
I'm in here!
Jack! I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
That guy Lovejoy put it in my pocket.
I know, I know...
Listen Rose...
you're gonna have to find the spare key, all right?
Look in that cabinet right there.
It's a little silver one, Rose.
These are all brass ones!
Check right here, Rose.
Rose.
How did you find out I didn't do it?
I didn't.
I just realized I already knew.
Keep looking.
No key.
There's no key!
All right, Rose, listen.
You're gonna have to go find some help.
It'll be all right.
I'll be right back.
I'll just wait here!
Hello? Is there anyone here?
Hello?
Is there anybody down here?
We need help! Hello?
Damnit!
Can anybody hear me, please?! Hello...
Oh, thank God.
Wait, please, I need your help.
There's a man back here and he's...
Wait!
Hello?!
Hello?
Miss, you shouldn't be here now.
I need your help.
There is a man down here and he is trapped.
- This way, yes. All right.  - Please!
- There's no need to panic.  - No, I'm not panicking!
You're going the wrong way!
Let go of me! Listen!!!
To hell with you.
Oh, my God.
Will this work?
I guess we'll find out.
Come on.
Wait, wait, wait.
Try a couple practice swings over there.
Good.
Now try and hit the same mark again, Rose. You can do it.
Okay, that's enough practice. Come on, Rose.
You can do it.
Listen, just hit it really hard and really fast.
Come on. Wait.
Open your hands up a little more.
- Like that?  - Right.
Listen, Rose, I trust you.
Go.
You did it!
Come on. Let's go.
Oh shit, this is cold! Oh, shit!
Shit! Shit!
This is the way out.
We have to find another way. Come on.
Pull.
Put your backs into it.
Pull!
Now, there's something you don't see every day.
What's this luggage doing here? Get rid of it. Get rid of it.
We need the room. Get rid of that. Out.
This way. Let go, sir. Get back.
Keep calm!
Lovejoy!
She's not on the starboard side either.
We're running out of time. This strutting martinet isn't letting any men on at all.
There's one on the other side letting men on.
Well then, that's our play.
We'll need some insurance first. Come on.
This way, please. All the way down here.
Here!
What do you think you're doing?
You'll have to pay for that, you know.
That's White Star Line property.
Shut up!
Will you hold the boat a moment? I just have to run back to my room...
Sit down!
She's the last.
- Prepare to lower.  - Mr. Lightoller.
Why are the boats being launched half full?
Not now, Mr. Andrews.
There, look. 20 or so in a boat built for 65?
And I saw one boat with only 12. 12!
Well, we weren't sure of the weight, Mr. Andrews.
These boats may buckle.
Rubbish!
They were tested in Belfast with the weight of 70 men.
Now, fill these boats, Mr. Lightoller. For God's sake, man!
Please, I need more women and children, please!
Get back in there!
This is not an exit. This is not an exit.
You can't keep us locked in here. Like animals. The ship's bloody sinking.
Bring forward the women!
Unlock the gates.
Women only!
No men!
Get back!
Lock the gates!
Get them back from those gates!
Don't touch the gates!
For God's sake, man...
there are women and children down here!
Let us up so we can have a chance!
Get back!
Tommy!
- Can we get out?  - It's hopeless that way.
Whatever we do, we've got to do it fast.
The boats are all going.
This whole place is flooding. We've gotta get out of here.
There is niente this way.
Let's go this way, all right? Come on!
I make my own luck.
So do I.
Come on!
No, come on, let's go this way.
This way!
Just go back to the main stairwell.
And everything will be sorted out there.
It will all get sorted out back there.
Go back to the main stairwell.
- Open the gate!  - Go back down the main stairwell.
Open the gate right now!
Go back down the main stairwell, like I told you.
Goddamn it! Son of a bitch!
Stop that!
Fabri, Tommy, give me a hand here.
Move aside.
Come on, pull!
Pull!
Move aside. Quickly, move aside!
Put that down!
- Move aside!  - Put that down!
One! Two!
Three!
Again!
Now, let's go!
Let's go, Rose.
You can't go up there! You can't do this!
Keep order! Keep order here!
Back! Back! Back!
Hold on to her!
Pull her in!
Get back, I say, or I'll...
shoot you all like dogs!
Keep order here!
Keep order, I say.
Mr. Lowe, man this boat.
Right. Is everybody all right? Nobody panic.
Stay back.
We're too late.
There are more boats down the front. Stay with this one. Murdoch.
He seems to be quite practical.
Don't lower it!
Cut the falls!
Sit down!
Stay back, you lot!
Just stay back, the lot of you! Stay back!
It's starting to fall apart. We don't have much time.
Mr. Murdoch?
Mr. Hockley. You two, with me, now!
I'm a businessman, as you know...
and I have a business proposition for you.
Come on, Rose.
The boats are gone!
Colonel, are there any boats on that side?
No, miss, but there are a couple of boats all the way forward.
This way, I'll lead you.
What's the use? Nobody's listening to us anyway.
Well, they don't listen to us at dinner, either.
Come on, let's play.
Keep us warm.
"Orpheus."
Music to drown by. Now I know I'm in first class.
- Where is everyone?  - They're all still aft, sir.
We have an understanding then, Mr. Murdoch.
Will the men please hold back! Hold back, I say!
Women and children only!
Get back!
Come through, madame. This way. Step back, sir!
You better check the other side. Go!
I found her, on the other side.
Waiting for a boat.
With him.
- Any more women and children?  - They're all aboard, Mr. Murdoch.
Anyone else then?
- Anyone else?  - Do hurry. Hurry along.
Goddamn it all to hell.
Shit.
Fire!
Sir, sir, you can't go through here.
That's it. Splendid. Right.
Prepare to lower.
Ready on the left.
Take them down.
Keep it steady.
Both sides together. Steady. Keep it steady.
- Give her to me.  - Daddy.
It'll be fine, darling. Don't you worry.
Daddy, get in the boat.
It's good-bye for a little while. Only for a little while.
There'll be another boat for the daddies.
This boat is for the mummies and the children.
You hold Mummy's hand and be a good little girl.
I'm not going without you.
No, you have to go, now.
No, Jack.
Get in the boat, Rose.
Yes.
Get on the boat!
Yes, get on the boat, Rose.
Oh my God, look at you.
You look a fright.
Here.
Put this on. Come.
Go on. I'll get the next one.
No, not without you.
I'll be all right. Listen, I'll be fine.
I'm a survivor, all right? Don't worry about me.
Now, go on. Get on.
I have an arrangement with an officer on the other side of the ship.
Jack and I can get off safely.
Both of us.
See?
I got my own boat to catch.
Go on, hurry.
They're almost full.
- Step aboard, miss.  - Go. Go.
Step aboard, please.
You're daddy's good girl, all right?
You're my little sailor.
Clear the rail, please.
And, lower away!
You're a good liar.
Almost as good as you.
There's no... there's no arrangement, is there?
No, there is.
Not that you'll benefit much from it.
I always win, Jack.
One way or another.
Rose!
Stop her!
Rose, what are you doing?!
No!
Rose! You're so stupid! Why did you do that, huh?
You're so stupid, Rose.
Why did you do that? Why?!
You jump, I jump, right?
Right.
Oh God. I couldn't go.
I couldn't go, Jack.
It's all right. We'll think of something.
- At least I'm with you.  - We'll think of something.
Come on! Move!
Come on! Move.
Come on!
Move!
Come on! Come on, Rose.
Rose, come on!
Move, Rose!
Go!
I hope you enjoy your time together!
What could possibly be funny?
I put the diamond in the coat.
And I put the coat on her!
Come on!
Dada!
We can't leave him.
All right, come on!
Dada!
Go back!
It's the wrong way! Come back!
No, not that way! Come back! Stop!
Go!
Go! Run!
This way!
Give me your hand!
Oh, God!
Help!
Wait, sir!
Sir, open the gate, please!
Help us, please!
Help us!
- Please!  - Please!
Bloody hell!
- Come on, come on!  - Come on!
Go, go!
Jesus.
- Please!  - Come on!
Hurry!
Come on!
I'm sorry, I dropped the keys.
- Wait, please!  - Wait!
Don't leave! Please, send for help!
I got it! Which one is it, Rose?
The short one. Try the short one.
Hurry, Jack.
Oh no! It won't go in.
It's stuck! It's stuck!
- Come on!  - Hurry, Jack!
- Hurry, Jack!  - Come on!
I got it! I got it! Go! Go, Rose!
Go! Go!
Jack! Come on!
Move, move.
- Get those oars in place.  - Get an oar under it.
Hold it! Hold it!
Hold it!
Get these davits cranked in! Let's get the falls hooked up!
Mommy!
Keep going up!
Stop pushing!
Stay back!
Will you give us a chance to live, you limey bastard!
I'll shoot any man who tries to get past me! Get back!
Bastard!
Get back!
We had a deal, damn you!
Your money can't save you any more than it could save me.
Get back!
Women and children only!
No, Tommy!
No, Will!
Now stand back, damn you!
Gently, gently. Hold it. Hold it.
I have a child!
- I have a child!  - Clear a path here!
Please, I have a child!
Please. I'm all she has in the world.
Go on.
Step back!
- Please?  - Here, give her to me.
You're all right, dearie.
Give her here.
There, there.
Wait, wait, wait! Mr. Andrews!
Oh, Rose.
Won't you even make a try for it?
I'm sorry that I didn't build you a stronger ship, young Rose.
It's going fast. We have to move.
Wait.
Good luck to you, Rose.
And to you.
Mr. Guggenheim?
These are for you, Mr. Guggenheim.
No, thank you.
We are dressed in our best and are prepared to go down as gentlemen.
But we would like a brandy.
Get the falls over here now!
Let them drop. Then we'll right it.
Captain?
Captain, where should I go? Please.
Captain. Captain. Sir.
Right. That's it, then.
Good-bye, Wally. Good luck.
- Good-bye, Wallace.  - So long, old chap.
And so they lived happily together for 300 years...
in the land of Tir na nog...
Land of eternal youth and beauty.
There's no time!
Cut those falls!
Cut them! Cut them if you have to!
I need a knife!
Cut the falls now!
Cut them loose!
Cut those bloody falls!
Gentlemen...
It has been a privilege playing with you tonight.
We have to stay on the ship as long as possible.
Come on!
This way. Through the rail.
Come on, Rose.
Jump.
Come on.
I got you. Jump.
I've got you, miss.
Back!
No! You'll swamp us!
Yea, though I walk through the valley of the shadow of death...
You wanna walk a little faster through that valley there?
Holy Mary, mother of God...
Pray for us sinners now and at the hour of our death. Amen.
Hail Mary, full of grace...
This way.
Come on!
And I saw a new heaven and a new earth...
for the first heaven and the first earth had passed away...
and there was no more sea.
It'll be over soon. It'll all be over soon.
And He shall dwell with them.
And they shall be His people and God Himself shall be with them...
and be their God.
Jack...
this is where we first met.
And God shall wipe away all the tears from their eyes...
and there shall be no more death.
Neither shall there be sorrow or crying.
Neither shall there be any more pain...
for the former world has passed away.
Bloody pull faster! And pull!
Hang on, miss Trudy!
Hold on real tight.
God Almighty.
Keep those breakers in! Keep them in!
We have to move!
Give me your hand. I'll pull you over.
I can't.
Come on!
Give me your hand.
I've got you. I won't let go.
Come on, I've got you.
- What's happening, Jack?  - I don't know. I don't know.
Hold on.
This is it!
Oh, my God, Jack! Oh, God. Oh, God.
Hold on!
The ship is gonna suck us down.
Take a deep breath when I say.
Kick for the surface and keep kicking.
Do not let go of my hand.
We're going to make it, Rose.
Trust me.
I trust you.
Ready! Ready!
Now!
Jack! Jack!
Rose!
Get off her! Get off her!
Swim, Rose! I need you to swim!
Keep swimming.
It's so cold.
Swim, Rose!
Come on.
Keep swimming.
Here...
get on it.
Get on top.
Come on, Rose.
Stay on it. Stay on, Rose.
It'll be all right now.
Return...
the boats!
The boats are coming back for us Rose.
Hold on just a little bit longer.
They had to row away for the suction...
but now they'll be coming back.
For God's sake!
Please...
help us!
You don't understand.
If we go back, they'll swamp the boat.
They'll pull us right down, I'm telling you.
Oh, knock it off. You're scaring me.
Come on, girls, grab an oar. Let's go.
Are you out of your mind? We're in the middle of the North Atlantic.
Now, do you people want to live or do you want to die?!
I don't understand a one of you.
What's the matter with you?
It's your men out there!
There's plenty of room for more.
And there'll be one less on this boat...
if you don't shut that hole in your face!
Now, bring in your oars over there. And tie these boats together as well.
Now, make sure that's tied up nice and tight.
Right, listen to me, men. We have to go back.
I want to transfer all the women from this boat into that boat right now...
as quick as you can, please.
Let's create some space over there. Move forward and aft.
It's getting quiet.
It's just going to take a couple of minutes...
to get the boats organized.
I don't know about you but...
I intend to write a strongly worded letter...
to the White Star Line about all this.
I love you, Jack.
Don't you do that.
Don't you say your good-byes. Not yet.
Do you understand me?
I'm so cold.
Listen, Rose...
you're gonna get out of here.
You're gonna go on...
and you're gonna make lots of babies.
And you're gonna watch them grow.
You're gonna die an old...
an old lady.
Warm in her bed.
Not here.
Not this night. Not like this.
Do you understand me?
I can't feel my body.
Winning that ticket, Rose...
was the best thing that ever happened to me.
It brought me to you.
And I'm thankful for that, Rose.
I'm thankful.
You must...
you must do me this honor.
You must promise me that you'll survive.
That you won't give up...
no matter what happens.
No matter how hopeless.
Promise me now, Rose.
And never let go of that promise.
I promise.
Never let go.
I'll never let go, Jack.
I'll never let go.
Right ahead, sir.
Oars!
Do you see any moving?
No, sir. None moving, sir.
Check them.
Bring that oar up here.
Check them. Make sure.
These are dead, sir.
Now, give way.
Ahead easy.
Careful with your oars.
Don't hit them.
Is there anyone alive out there?
Can anyone hear me?
We waited too long.
Well, keep checking them!
Keep looking!
Is there anyone alive out there?
Can anyone hear me?
Come, Josephine...
in my flying machine
And it's up she goes
Up she goes
Come, Josephine...
in my flying...
Jack.
There's a boat.
There's a boat, Jack.
Come back.
Come back. Come back!
Hello!
Can anyone hear me?
There's nothing here, sir.
Come back.
I'll never let go.
I promise.
Come about!
Fifteen hundred people went into the sea...
when Titanic sank from under us.
There were twenty boats floating nearby...
and only one came back.
One.
Six were saved from the water...
myself included.
Six...
out of fifteen hundred.
Afterward...
the seven hundred people in the boats...
had nothing to do but wait.
Wait to die.
Wait to live.
Wait for an absolution...
that would never come.
Sir, I don't think you'll find any of your people down here.
It's all steerage.
His hair is reddish brown, reddish brown, reddish brown.
White beard.
Isn't there another passenger list?
There is no other list.
Perhaps he's on another ship.
We're doing all we can, ma'am. I'm so sorry.
That's the last time I ever saw him.
He married. Of course. And inherited his millions.
But the Crash of '29 hit his interests hard...
and he put a pistol in his mouth that year.
Or so I read.
Can I take your name please, love?
Dawson.
Rose Dawson.
Thank you.
We never found anything on Jack.
There's no record of him at all.
No, there wouldn't be, would there?
And I've never spoken of him until now.
Not to anyone.
Not even your grandfather.
A woman's heart is a deep ocean of secrets.
But now you know there was a man named Jack Dawson...
and that he saved me...
in every way that a person can be saved.
I don't even have a picture of him.
He exists now only in my memory.
Keldysh, Mir 2 on our way to the surface.
I was saving this for when I found the diamond.
I'm sorry.
Three years...
I've thought of nothing except Titanic.
But I never got it.
I never let it in.